welcome back
today we are going to harness the power of the core
and the first thing we are going to need is some tiberium
this can be obtained on Ross's moon
which requires a tier 5 rocket
we quickly craft it
and then launch to our new adventure
once we arrive at the new destination
the first thing we notice is how fast the day passes here
and after some prospecting
we quickly find some Tiberium
after collecting some of it
we quickly craft the new fuel rods
then after doing a backup
we try to see how it behaves inside a nuclear reactor
and it looks like our current system can barely handle those rods
the real issue is that
due to the huge heat produced by such fuel
if our coolant system were to fail
the reactor will instantly evaporate
to contain the mess in case of explosion
we can add some reactor platings
or by adding enough heat capacity plates
we can make our reactor able to tank
up to four seconds of exposure to such powerful fuel
and that should be enough time for our Thermal Protection to trigger
and thus
we came up with this design
where there are six rods
each with four dedicated coolant cells
the power output is 600 thousand EU per tick
doubling what we had before
however that didn't last long
it looks like
some heat managed to escape to the reactor hull
and triggered our Thermal Protection
and the culprit seems to be our underpaid vacuum freezer
which is still working only on MV wage
so we gave it a rise to EV
however our power balance is now negative again
so we must find a more powerful design
and after some crafting
we can finally use the 40 rods famous one
this configuration is extremely dangerous
because there is nothing saving our base
if the reactor were to run with a too low amount of coolant
to do a quick test
we are going to run the reactor for a second
with the help of a button and a screwdriver
and here
we can see that our coolants took quite the hit from just that small run
we can do a second push
and see that we are already over half of the coolant
but the power output is really high
now we shall try to find a way of automating that thing
to do so
we need three buttons and lamps
the first one will run the reactor
the second one will extract the coolant
and it appears that this is going to need more than a push to finish its job
once the exhaust is out
we can use the third button to insert new fresh coolant cells
managing to automate cells that get burned up so fast
is going to be too risky and hard
so we shall instead switch to some bigger ones
the issue is that those require fluxed electrum
which has to be cooked in a ZPM
trinium coil DBF
and trinium coils require a ZPM assembler
since we already have all the requirements
we quickly rush the ZPM assembler
which we use to upgrade our volcanoes
thus
allowing for the crafting of the best coolant cells
now that we have better coolant
we can start using levers instead of buttons
we carefully turn on the reactor
and watch as it works
and when we turn it off
some fire happens
fear not
that was just our thin cable that couldn't handle the power output of our reactor
we shall switch to the only cable capable of handling so many amps
superconductor 16x
once the new cable is in place
we can go back to our tests
and move to stage 2
extracting the used coolant
finally in the third stage
we insert new fresh coolant
and we are ready for another iteration of the loop
however
that is not how we are going to do it
we want it to be automatically managed by a timer
but we can't be careless and just directly connect it
we will want to have some extra sensors
namely something that stops the thing if we run out of coolant
after some fiddling
we set up a system that will output a signal
if we have less than a change of cells
while at it
we also add a lever to manually shout down the reactor
then we connect everything up
and it was finally time to let that thing run on its own
since one whole iteration takes 7 seconds
we can speed it up by seven times
and now there are two main issues
the first one
is that we are not receiving the power output
which turned out to be a limitation of the plug of our battery
this setup is making 150 amps
and we could only absorb spikes of 80
the second issue is that
this setup is not going to produce our 150 amps LuV constantly
but only 1/4 of the time
now exactly like a 4 strokes engine
that is okay if we have a light load with some inertia
but not when we need a lot of power
so to make a good nuclear engine
we are going to need three more cylinders filled with cylinders of cylinders of enriched naquadah
that required a lot of tiberium
and here came the realization
cooking all the tungsten steel for those cylinders
is going to take quite some time
too much time
to do that in a reasonable amount of time
we shall have a bigger blast furnace
that thing is going to cook our tungsten steel twice as fast
but it is also making way more pollution
also
we are now using more power
than what our single four strokes reactor can make
and after some time
we finally managed to finish our inline 4 engine
now let's see in the details how that thing works
every reactor has the same setup of the one we had before
however
we changed the working conditions
and the four reactors have a 90 degrees phase offset
the new condition is that
instead of just checking the coolant level
we have a red wire that will allow for running
that red wire is the output of an and gate
of a lever, our coolant level and our battery level
for both the levels
we have an RS latch
that will allow for smoother working
and we wait up to 30 seconds
before reenabling the reactors
if we run low on coolant
and since the coolant is swapped even if the reactor doesn't run
we can filter the unused cells
to not go through the vacuum freezer
that's how the setup works with a 7x speed up
and while that thing can keep our batteries well charged up
we can do even better
we can do so by using a more optimal fuel layout
in this configuration
each rod has exactly three nearby rods and one coolant cell
that way the fuel is pushed to the maximum
also every coolant cells has exactly one rod to cool
making it last the longest time possible
that will also lead to cells taking all the exact same damage
making it possible to easily filter them out of the reactor when they reach critical damage
finally
we can fill the reactor with enough heat capacity plates
to make it able to withstand the loss of one cell
meaning that we can try to automate the cell swap while the reactor runs
and for more ease
we must ensure all the cells are at a different damage level
so that only one has to be replaced or can fail every reactor tick
and it was then
that I was unsure if it was an error or not following errors advice
anyways
this setup seems to make quite enough power
and to finish off
we add a condition that will turn on the reactors
only when our battery reaches a quarter of charge
and that is quite some toggling
but with such a setup there is no need for latches
anyways
I think we have fixed the power issues for at least one episode
see you next time
bye bye
欢迎回来！
今天我们要利用"核心"发电
首先需要的是一些泰伯利亚矿
可以在罗斯的卫星上挖掘
这要 T5 火箭
我们快速制作它
然后开始新的冒险
一旦我们到达新的目的地
可以注意到这里一天的时间飞逝
经过一番勘探
我们很快找到了一些泰伯利亚矿
收集了一些后
迅速做点新燃料棒
在进行备份后
我们尝试观察它在核反应堆中的行为
看起来我们现有的系统几乎无法处理这些燃料棒
真正的问题是
由于此燃料棒带来的巨量热量
如果冷却系统失灵
反应堆会瞬间被蒸发
以防发生爆炸
我们可以添加一些反应堆板
或者通过添加足够的热容量板
让我们的反应堆
在如此强大的燃料下承受长达 4 秒钟
4 秒足够启动热防护系统了
因此
我们得到这个设计
总共有六个燃料棒
每个燃料棒都有四个专用的冷却单元
输出功率高达 600 kEU/t
比以前多了一倍
然而这并没有持续多久
似乎
一些热量设法逃逸到反应堆外壳
触发了我们的热防护系统
罪魁祸首似乎是我们低能效的冰箱
它仍然只以 MV 电压工作
所以我们将其升至 EV
然而现在的电力收支又转成赤字
所以我们必须找到更强大的设计
经过一番精心制作
也是用上了最出名的 40 燃料棒设计
这种配置极其危险
如果反应堆的冷却单元太少
我们的基地就等待毁灭吧
做一个快速测试
在按钮和螺丝刀的帮助下
我们让反应堆运行一秒
我们可以看到冷却单元受到了不小的冲击
再按一次
已经有一半的冷却单元出现问题
但输出功率真的很高
现在我们尝试找到一种自动化的方法
为此
我们需要三个按钮和灯
第一个将运行反应堆
第二个会抽出冷却单元
看来想完成工作不仅仅只是按一次那么简单
一旦抽取
我们用第三个按钮插入新的冷却单元
想给损毁如此快的单元自动化
实在是太冒险了
所以我们应该换一些容量大的
问题是那些需要通流琥珀金
它必须在 ZPM 电压
使用三元金属线圈的高炉烧制
而三元金属线圈需要 ZPM 组装机
既然已经有了需求
我们就快速做出 ZPM 组装机
用它来升级炽焰高炉
由此
制作出最好的冷却单元
有了它们
可以将拉杆换掉按钮了
我们小心地打开反应堆
看着它工作
当我们关掉它时
有些火焰冒了出来
不要害怕
这是线缆最大荷载太低导致的
我们切换至唯一能胜任这个工作的线缆
LuV 超导线缆 16x
一旦新电缆到位
我们回到测试
进入第二阶段
抽取用过的冷却单元
最后是第三阶段
插入新的冷却单元
这样就能进行下一个循环了
然而
这不是我们想要达成的效果
我们想用计时器自动控制
不要粗心地直接把计时器接入电路
我们需要一些额外的传感器
在冷却单元用尽后自动停止
经过一番摆弄
我们设置了一套系统
只要缺少了冷却单元就会输出信号
同时
还增加了一个拉杆来手动控制
然后把一切都连接起来
是时候让它自己运行了
因为整个迭代需要 7 秒
所以我们加速 7 倍
现在有两个主要问题
第一
我们没有收到能量输出
这是能源仓的问题
这套核电输出了 150A 的电流
但电池只能接收 80A
第二个问题是
它不会持续产生 150A LuV
只有四分之一的时间在输出
就像一个四冲程引擎
如果负载较轻并带有惯性的话，那也没问题
但高负载时就力不从心
所以想造一个优质核电
满载硅岩燃料的另外三台核电很必须
而这也需要大量的硅岩
然后我意识到
为这些单元烧完钨钢
需要相当长的时间
难以忍受的长
要在合理的时间内做到这一点
少不了巨高炉
那东西能以两倍的速度烧制钨钢
但也有更多污染
而且
我们现在的耗能
比单个四冲程反应堆产生的还多
一段时间后
我们终于完成了“四联引擎”
让我们详细看看它是如何工作的
每个反应堆都和之前的一样
然而
我们改变了工作条件
而且四个反应堆各有90度的相位偏移
新的条件是
不仅是检查冷却单元的损伤
我们用一条红线控制反应堆启停
那条红线是与门的输出
结合了拉杆、冷却单元数量和电池电量
对于后两个红石信号
我们用一个 RS 锁存器
来使反应堆工作更顺畅
如果冷却单元用完了
我们要等 30 秒
才会重启反应堆
因为即使反应堆不运行冷却单元也会被交换
我们过滤未使用的单元
不让它再进入冰箱
这就是产线 7 倍速工作的样子
虽说那东西能让电池饱餐一顿
我们可以做得更好
通过使用更优化的燃料布局
在此配置中
每根燃料棒附近正好有三根燃料棒和一个冷却单元
这样燃料的使用率最高
每个冷却单元只有一个燃料棒要冷却
使其持续尽可能长的时间
这也会导致冷却单元受到完全相同的损伤
就可以很容易地将达到临界损坏的冷却单元过滤出反应堆
终于
我们可以用足够的热容量板填充反应堆
使它能够承受一个冷却单元的损失
这意味着我们可以在反应堆运行时更换冷却单元
为了更轻松点
我们必须确保所有冷却单元处于不同的损伤水平
这样每个反应堆刻只有一个单元要更换或过热损毁
就在那时
我不确定没有遵循 Error 的建议是否是个错误
不管怎样
这个装置能产足够的电了
最后
我们增加一个条件来启动反应堆
当电池电量低于四分之一
这产生了相当多的启停
但这样的设置不需要锁存器
不管怎样
我想我们至少解决了一集的电力问题
下次见
拜拜
（简介放了用GT传送带做的丐版自动化，还有原作者对它的态度）
（我跟原作者聊了，他说的 Error 这个人给的建议是指上面这个反应堆）